A Guide to the Additional Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr., ca. 1924-2003
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Additional Papers of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. ca. 1924-2003
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10320-g
This addition to the papers of United States Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. consists of ca. 28,500 items (89 boxes and 10 OS boxes, ca. 59 linear feet).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access to the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers is controlled by the Honorable Harry F. Byrd, Jr. An applicant for access who is not associated with the University of Virginia must furnish to the Director of Special Collections a brief description of his academic or other qualifications, a summary of his research project, and a description of any projected publication that might make use of material from, or material derived from, the Harry F. Byrd, Jr., Papers. The Director of Special Collections will contact Senator Byrd and will notify the applicant of the Senator's decision.
Acquisition Information
These additional Harry Flood Byrd, Jr. Papers were added to the materials, originally deeded to the University of Virginia Library on February 2, 1979, by Senator Byrd on November 25, 2000.
Biographical/Historical Information
Harry Flood Byrd, Jr., a former member of the Virginia Senate (1947-1965), United States Senator for Virginia (1965-1983), and newspaper executive, was born in Winchester, Virginia, on December 20, 1914, son of Harry F. Byrd, Sr. and Anne Douglas (Beverley) Byrd. He was a student at the Virginia Military Institute, 1931-1933, and the University of Virginia, 1933-1935. Byrd married Gretchen B. Thomson of New Orleans, on August 9, 1941, and they had three children, Harry, Thomas Thomson, and Beverley.
Appointed to the United States Senate in 1965, Senator Byrd was elected to the Senate in 1966 as a Democrat and was reelected in 1970 and 1976 as an Independent. He was the first person in the history of the Senate to be elected twice as an Independent. Byrd was active on both the Armed Services Committee and the Finance Committee. He was also a member of the Virginia Democratic Central Committee (1940-1966).
Byrd was the editor of the Winchester Evening Star from 1935-, publisher of the Harrisonburg, Virginia, Daily News Record, 1937-; President and Director of the Rockingham Publishing Company, from 1946; director of the Associated Press, 1950-1966.
During World War II, he served as an executive officer of a patrol bombing squadron in the Central and Western Pacific as a Lieutenant Commander in the United States Naval Reserve. Byrd was a recipient of the Honor Medal, and a member of the Veterans of Foreign Wars, the American Legion, Rotarian Club, National Press Club, and the Army-Navy Club. Byrd also served on the boards of many educational and other institutions and received many awards from civic groups too numerous to mention in this short note. For additional information see the membership files and the list of plaques awarded to the Senate in appreciation of his career of service.
Scope and Content
This addition to the papers of United States Senator Harry F. Byrd, Jr. consists of ca. 28,500 items (89 boxes and 10 OS boxes, ca. 59 linear feet), ca. 1924-2003, including correspondence, speeches, campaign materials, memberships on boards and organizations, photographs, plaques, memorabilia, awards, Senate voting records and topical files.
Much of the material deals with the political campaigns of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. for the Virginia State Legislature and the United States Senate, working files from his terms in the Virginia and U.S. Senate, correspondence concerning his decision to retire from the Senate, and files pertaining to his stint as the editor of the Winchester Star, and other family owned newspapers.
The first series consists of correspondence; correspondents in the alphabetical correspondence subseries (Boxes 1-12) discuss the Byrd apple orchards, his editorials, personal matters, and issues in the Virginia Legislature. The political subseries of correspondence (Boxes 13-19) chiefly discusses Byrd's campaign for the Senate in 1970 and his decision to run as an Independent, his political contributors, and information about the campaign. There are also a good many letters concerning his decision to retire when his term was up in 1983.
The second series (Boxes 20-40) provides a good idea of the extent of Senator Byrd's involvement in public activities including festivals, commissions, memberships in various organizations, college boards of trustees, special awards, and historical and cultural organizations. This series also includes files on "Special Friends" listed in the folder listing, and speeches by Byrd, chiefly after his Senate career.
The next series is subdivided into the business papers (Boxes 41-47) of Senator Byrd, including files about his newspaper business, investments, and H.F.Byrd, Inc. and his family and personal papers (Boxes 48- 52), which includes files on his wedding anniversaries, articles by Byrd, awards and certificates, his wife, Gretchen, family correspondence, news clippings about Byrd, photographs of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. in various settings and with his family, notable figures and celebrities, a few of Harry F. Byrd, Sr., and his South Pole trip in 1979.
The majority of material in the fourth series of campaign and political papers deals with the 1976 election but there are scattered files on campaigns and politics in other years. There were several political surveys conducted for Byrd by professional companies and material concerning the Virginians for Byrd organization. There also appears to be a complete record of the Senate Roll Call Votes of Harry F. Byrd, Jr. (Boxes 72-80) and an almost complete Voting Record (Boxes 80-81).
The fifth series is devoted to the plaques awarded to Byrd and other miscellaneous memorabilia.
Arrangement
These papers are organized in five series:
Series I. Correspondence: Subseries A: Alphabetical Correspondence (Boxes 1-12) Subseries B: Political and Retirement from Senate (Boxes 13- 19)
Series II Public Activities (Boxes 20-40) Series III Personal, Family, and Business Papers Subseries A: Business (Boxes 41-47) Subseries B: Family and Personal Papers (Boxes 48-52 and OS Box S-74)
Series IV Campaign and Political Papers (Boxes 52-89 ) Subseries A: Campaign Papers, 1966-1976, (Boxes 52-56) Subseries B: Political: 1976 Election (Boxes 57-64 ) Subseries C: Political: Miscellaneous (Boxes 65-71, and OS Box S-75) Subseries D: Political Notebooks (Boxes 72-81)
Series V Plaques Awarded to Harry F. Byrd, Jr. and Byrd Miscellany (Boxes 82-89 and S-76 through S- 82).
Contents List
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Subseries A: Alphabetical Correspondence
    - Correspondence: A 1950-1954 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence: A (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence: B (5 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence: B 1958 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Ba-Be 1959 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Bi-By 1959 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: B 1960 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Ba-Be 1961 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Bi-By 1961 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Ba-Be 1962 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: Bi-By 1962 (Box 2)
    - Correspondence: C (5 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: C (4 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: D 1950-1952 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence: D 1953-1954 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: D (3 folders) 1959-1961 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Da-Dr 1962 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: Du-Dw 1962 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: E 1950-1954 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: E (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: F (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: F 1959 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence: F (2 folders) 1960-1962 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence: G (3 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence: G (4 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence: H (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: H 1959 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: Hag-Haw 1960 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: He-Hu 1960 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: Ha 1961 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: He-Hy 1961 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: Ha 1962 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: He-Hy 1962 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence: I-J 1950-1954 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: I-J 1959-1962 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: K (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: K (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: L (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: L (2 folders) 1959-1960 (Box 7)
    - Correspondence: L (2 folders) 1961-1962 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence: Mc 1950-1954 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence: Mc (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence: M (4 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence: M (3 folders) 1959-1961 (Box 8)
    - Correspondence: M 1962 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: N 1950-1954 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: N (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: O 1950-1954 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: O 1959-1962 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: P-Q (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: P-Q (3 folders) 1959-1961 (Box 9)
    - Correspondence: P-Q 1962 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence: R (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence: R (4 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence: S (4 folders)) 1950-1953 (Box 10)
    - Correspondence: S 1954 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: S (3 folders) 1959-1961 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: Sa-Sm 1962 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: Sn-Sy 1962 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: T (2 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: T (3 folders) 1959-1962 (Box 11)
    - Correspondence: U-V 1950-1954 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: U-V 1959-1962 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: W-Z ( 5 folders) 1950-1954 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: W-Z (3 folders) 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Wa-Wh 1962 (Box 12)
    - Correspondence: Wi-Z 1962 (Box 12)
  - Subseries B: Correspondence: Political and Retirement from Senate
    - Correspondence: Political and Business Letters 1950-1951 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political and Business Letters 1952 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1969 (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Jan-Mar (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Apr-Jun (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Jul-Aug (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Sep (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Oct (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1970 Nov-Dec (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1971 Jan-Feb (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1971 Mar-May (Box 13)
    - Correspondence: Political 1971 Jun-Sep (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1971 Oct-Dec (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Jan-Feb (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Mar-May (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Jun-Jul (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Aug-Sep (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Oct (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political 1972 Nov-1973 Jan (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors A-B 1970 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors C-F 1970 (Box 14)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors G-H 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors I-M 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors N-R 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors S-Z 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) A 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) B 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) C 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) D-E 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) F-G 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) H 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) I-L 1970 (Box 15)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) M 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) N-P 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) Q-R 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) S 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) T-V 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Political Contributors (Smith Ferebee File) W-Z 1970 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Responses to Congratulatory Letters on Byrd's Re-election 1970 Nov 16 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Retirement 1981 Nov 30-Dec2 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (3 folders) 1981 Dec 3-7 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (6 folders) 1981 Dec 8-28 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (3 folders) 1982 Jan 4-29 (Box 17)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (4 folders) 1982 Feb-Nov (Box 18)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (5 folders) 1982 Dec 1-20 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence: Retirement 1982 Dec 21-30 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Retirement 1983 Jan (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Retirement 1983 Feb-Mar (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Retirement: Members of Congress Letters 1981 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Retirement: Members of Congress Letters 1982 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Retirement (Special Letters Notebook) 1981-1982 (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Support 1969-1970 Feb (Box 19)
    - Correspondence: Support 1970 Mar (Box 19)
- Series II: Public Activities: Appointment Books and Files
  - Appointment Books (8 volumes) 1966-1970 (Box 20)
  - Appointment Books (9 volumes) 1970-1974 (Box 21)
  - Appointment Books (8 volumes) 1975-1978 (Box 22)
  - Appointment Books (8 volumes) 1979-1983 (Box 23)
  - Apple Blossom Festival (4 folders) 1956-1977 (Box 24)
  - Apple Blossom Festival 2002 (Box 24)
  - Apple Blossom Festival: Queens from 1924-1950 1950 (Box 24)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Monument Commission 1974-1975 Jun (Box 24)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Monument Commission 1975 Jul-Sep (Box 24)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Monument Commission 1975 Oct 6-20 (Box 25)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Monument Commission 1975 Oct 21-Dec (Box 25)
  - Harry F. Byrd, Sr. Monument Commission 1976-1978 (Box 25)
  - Invitations 1996-2000, n.d. (Box 25)
  - Invitations: Accepted 1982 (Box 25)
  - Invitations: Accepted (3 folders) 1983 (Box 25)
  - Invitations: Accepted (2 folders) 1984 (Box 26)
  - Invitations: Regrets 1982 Jul-Dec (Box 26)
  - Invitations: Regrets (3 folders) 1983 (Box 26)
  - Invitations: Regrets (2 folders) 1984 (Box 26)
  - Memberships: The Alfalfa Club (3 folders) 1958-1978 (Box 26)
  - Memberships: The Alfalfa Club Programs 1949-1998 (Box 27)
  - Memberships: American Academy of Achievement Banquet of the Golden Plate 1977 (Box 27)
  - Memberships: American Council for Capital Formation Board of Directors 1982 Dec-1983 Oct (Box 27)
  - Memberships: American Council for Capital Formation Board of Directors 1983 Nov-1984 Sep (Box 27)
  - Memberships: American Council for Capital Formation Board of Directors 1984 Oct-Nov (Box 27)
  - Memberships: American Frontier Culture Foundation 1980-1984 (Box 27)
  - Memberships: Blue Ridge Parkway 50th Anniversary Celebration Committee 1983-1984 (Box 28)
  - Memberships: Bridgewater College Board of Trustees 1977 Oct-1978 Oct (Box 28)
  - Memberships: Bridgewater College Board of Trustees 1978 Nov-1979 Aug (Box 28)
  - Memberships: Bridgewater College Board of Trustees 1979 Sep-Dec (Box 28)
  - Memberships: Bridgewater College Board of Trustees (3 folders) 1980-1982 (Box 28)
  - Memberships: Bridgewater College Institutional Self-Study Report 1980 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: Cards c. 1975-2003 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: Committee for a Single Six-Year Presidential Term 1983-1984 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: Committee to Fight Inflation 1983-1985 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: The Franklin Mint (3 folders) 1973-1976 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: Freedom's Foundation at Valley Forge: Awards 1973-1980 (Box 29)
  - Memberships: Freedom's Foundation at Valley Forge Board of Trustees (2 folders) 1972-1981 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: George C. Marshall Research Foundation 1975-1982 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: Government 1973-1980 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: Honorary A-F 1973-1981, 1995 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: Honorary L-Y 1971-1978 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: MacArthur Foundation 1973-1980 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: Miscellaneous 1950, 1973-1982 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: National Police Officers Association of America 1971-1982 (Box 30)
  - Memberships: National Taxpayers Union (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 31)
  - Memberships: National Taxpayers Union: Letters Regarding Wall Street Journal Ad 1984-1985 (Box 31)
  - Memberships: Park Communications Board of Directors (4 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 31)
  - Memberships: Patrick Henry Memorial Foundation Board of Trustees 1974-1981 (Box 32)
  - Memberships: Public Service A-M 1972-1982 (Box 32)
  - Memberships: Public Service N-W 1974-1981 (Box 32)
  - Memberships: Senate Youth Program 1974, 1980-1981 (Box 32)
  - Memberships: Shenandoah College Board of Trustees (3 folders) 1973-1979 (Box 32)
  - Memberships: Shenandoah College Board of Trustees (3 folders) 1980-1984 (Box 33)
  - Memberships: Tax Foundation Annual Dinners 1997-2003 (Box 33)
  - Memberships: Tax Foundation Board of Trustees (4 folders) 1973-1980 (Box 33)
  - Memberships: Tax Foundation Board of Trustees (2 folders) 1981-1984 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: U.S. Armed Forces Athletic Associations 1974-1981 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: Virginia Communications Hall of Fame 2003 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: Virginia Historical Society Board of Trustees (2 folders) 1983-1984 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: Virginia Orchestra Group, Norfolk - Board of Directors 1979 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: Washington National Monument Society (2 folders) 1973-1980 (Box 34)
  - Memberships: Washington National Monument Society 1981-1982 (Box 35)
  - Memberships: Woodrow Wilson Birthplace Foundation 1973-1974, 1980 (Box 35)
  - Memberships: Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars 1973-1980 (Box 35)
  - Memberships: Declined (3 folders) 1973-1981 (Box 35)
  - Newsletters 1967-1970 (Box 35)
  - Newsletters 1971-1982 (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: Clippings arranged by subject 1977-1981 (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: Drafts 1968-1970 (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: Masthead and Headlines n.d. (Box 36)
  - Newsletters: Research 1966-1973 (Box 36)
  - Publicity: Correspondence regarding, including an analysis of Byrd's newsletter (1972) 1962-1972 (Box 36)
  - Special Friends: 1973-1982 (Box 36)
    A-B, including John Adams, Maryon P. Allen, Ricardo Manuel Espinosa Arias, Alfred L. Atherton, Marilyn Atwood, Halford Baker, Joseph H. Ball, Polan Banks, Sam T. Barfield, Dewey F. Bartlett, Bernard M. Baruch, Jr., Richard F. Beirne, Edgar Bergen, Richard Berlin, James B. Beverley, III, J. Gray Beverley, Jr., D. Woodrow Bird, Anthony A. Bliss, T. MacAulay Booth, Thomas C. Boushall, George Bowles, J. Stewart Bryan, III, James L. Buckley, James A. Burden
  - Special Friends: Marshall J. Beverly 1974-1981 (Box 36)
  - Special Friends: Tennant Bryan 1975-1980, 1998 (Box 37)
  - Special Friends: 1973-1982 (Box 37)
    C-D, including Harry L. Carrico, Champlain H. Carson, Jr., Carl T. Cather, Turner Catledge, Christopher Chancellor, John A. Clem, III, J.D. Stetson Coleman, Thomas F. Connolly, Joseph Costello, Charlene B. Craycraft, Albert B. Crutcher, Jr., Carl T. Curtis, Jack F. Davis, S. Cooper, Dawson, Jr., Lester L. Dillard, George Dixon
  - Special Friends: 1973-1981 (Box 37)
    E-F, including David Eisenhower, Sam J. Ervin, Jr., Doug Fairbanks, J. Smith Ferebee, Earl A. Fitzpatrick, James William Fletcher, Frank D. Floyd, Henry H. Fowler, Samuel B. Fray, and Fred Funkhouser
  - Special Friends: 1973-1982 (Box 37)
    G-K, including Ashraf A. Ghorbal, Duncan C. Gibb, Fred L. Glaize, Thomas R. Glass, Freeman Gosden, Billy Graham, Elmon T. Gray, Raymond R. Guest, Clifford P. Hansen, Albertis S. Harrison, Jr., Hildreth V. Harrison, Frank B. Hayne, William R. Hearst, Jr., John P. Humes, Lewis H. Hyde, John H. Kauffman, Sidney S. Kellam, Joseph Kingbury-Smith
  - Special Friends: Mills E. Godwin (5 folders) 1966-1976 (Box 37)
  - Special Friends: Mills E. Godwin 1977-1982 (Box 38)
  - Special Friends: Eliot Janeway 1975-1982 (Box 38)
  - Special Friends: 1973-1982 (Box 38)
    L-M, including Scott Lacher, William H. Landrum, Edward B. Lee, Bernard Levin, Lawrence Lewis, Jr., Carter O. Lowance, Neila B. Mackrell, John H. Maginnis, Warren G. Magnuson, Joseph A. Massie, Jr., Frank McCarthy, Lin Mehemel, M.J. Menefee, Henry P. Mitchell, George Murphy, William R. Murphy
  - Special Friends: J.C. Miller 1975-1981 (Box 38)
  - Special Friends: Paul Miller 1973-1982 (Box 38)
  - Special Friends: 1977-1982 (Box 38)
    N-R, including William Neurdenburg, Lloyd U. Noland, Jr., Marilyn Odom, Carter H. Ogden, E. Walton Opie, Hierome L. Opie, Voltaire Perkins, Lewis F. Powell, Jr., Eugene Pulliam, E.R. Quesada, John B. Rawlings, Phillip Rayfield, J. Philip Reberger, Abraham A. Ribicoff, Joe Richman, William S. Robertson
  - Special Friends: 1968-1982 (Box 38)
    S, including James Savedge, Richard M. Scaife, Randolph Scott, Thomas G. Scully, Richard T. Short, David G. Simpson, D. French Slaughter, Louis Spilman, William B. Spilman, Harry F. Stimpson, Jr. James Stone, Lewis L. Strauss, George E. Stringfellow, Albert Swanke, G. Fred Switzer, John J. Synon
  - Special Friends: 1974-1981 (Box 38)
    T-Z, including Stuart S. Taylor, C.E. Thurston, Jr., Lewis H. Vaden, John W. Warner, George W. Warren, McDonald Wellford, John W. Williams, Langbourne M. Williams, B. Beverley Wright, William L. Zimmer, Jr.
  - Special Friends: William Tuck 1973-1981 (Box 38)
  - Speeches 1968-1970 (Box 38)
  - Speeches: Opening 1970 Campaign 1970 (Box 38)
  - Speeches: Welcome Home Dinner, Winchester 1983 Feb 10 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: West Richmond Businessmen's Association 1983 May 9 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Harrison Rotary Club 1983 May 23 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Statement on the Death of William M. Tuck 1983 Jun 9 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Spotswood High School, Penn Laird, Virginia 1983 Jun 10 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Dedication of Fort Harrison, Dayton, Virginia 1983 Jun 11 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: National Society of the Sons of the American Revolution National Congress, Atlanta, Georgia 1983 Jun 21 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Dedication of the Historical Marker Honoring the Salyer Family, Russell County, Virginia 1983 Aug 21 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Dedication of Alumni Hall, University of Virginia 1983 Sep 9 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: United Fund Kick-off Luncheon 1983 Sep 14 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Potomac Lodge No. 5 1983 Oct 17 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Sons of the American Revolution, Martinsburg, West Virginia 1983 Oct 21 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Virginia Woman's Forum, John Marshall Hotel, Richmond, Virginia 1983 Nov 10 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Presentation of the Thomas Jefferson Award for Public Service to Anne Dobie Peebles 1983 Dec 1 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Miller Center Forum, University of Virginia (1 of 2 folders) 1983 Dec 5 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: Miller Center Forum, University of Virginia (2 of 2 folders) 1983 Dec 5 (Box 39)
  - Speeches: New Comen Society, Virginia Military Institute 1984 Mar 26 (Box 40)
  - Speeches: Virginia National Guard Association, Williamsburg, Virginia 1984 Mar 31 (Box 40)
  - Speeches: Boy Scouts of America, Tidewater Council, Norfolk, Virginia 1984 April 2 (Box 40)
  - Speeches -Nature Conservancy, Richmond, Virginia 1984 Apr 25 (Box 40)
  - Speeches -West Richmond Businessmen's Association 1984 May 14 (Box 40)
  - Speeches: Bridgewater College Graduation 1984 May 27 (Box 40)
  - Speeches: Monacan High School Graduation, Chesterfield County, Virginia 1984 Jun 12 (Box 40)